Guide to the Douglas Merritt Whitaker Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Douglas Merritt Whitaker papers
1926-1963
SC0176
Whitaker, Douglas Merritt, 1904-1973.
3 Linear feet
Papers include articles, speeches, slides used in lecture on evolution, some correspondence and lecture notes, and material on the Bikini atom bomb tests.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Edith Whitaker, 1977.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of Biology at Stanford (1931-1955); Dean of the School of Biological Sciences (1946-1949); Dean of Graduate Studies (1948-1951); Dean of Humanities and Sciences (1951-1952). Acting Vice-President of the University (1948-1949); and Provost (1952-1955). Also served as chief biologist for the Bikini atom bomb tests.
Description of the Collection
Papers include articles, speeches, slides used in lecture on evolution, some correspondence and lecture notes, and material on the Bikini atom bomb tests.
Access Terms
Hopkins Marine Station; Stanford University. Department of Zoology. Faculty.; Stanford University. School of Biological Sciences.; Whitaker, Douglas Merritt, 1904-1973.; Atomic bomb.; Bikini Atoll (Pacific Islands); Slides.; Speeches.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Volume of articles and reprints, 1926-44. Index (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles and reprints, 1945-51 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical material to March 1953. List of publications to 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bikini Project, summer 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes, course on evolution, 1944-50 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photos of unidentified slides, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1946-53 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1955-63 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2 boxes: slides re Bikini Project, summer 1947 (Box 2)
  - 1 box: slides re course on evolution, 1944-50 (Box 2)